Either you translate it,
you explain it to me,
what is in the knowledge of
Allah,
or knowledge about Allah's
essence himself.
That our knowledge cannot
encompass it,
about Allah's essence,
everything about it,
no.
Or about the things inside
his knowledge,
subhanahu wa ta'ala.
Our own knowledge cannot
encompass everything.
What that means is that he is
ever absolutely more
knowledgeable
than all of us in every
circumstance,
subhanahu wa ta'ala.
So, Allah is alamu in every
circumstance.
This is wa anna allaha qad
ahata
bi kulli shay'in ilmah.
Allah subhanahu wa ta'ala,
his knowledge encompasses
everything,
ahata bi kulli shay'in.
As for Banu Adam,
our own knowledge is small.
Very small knowledge.
When he spoke about our
knowledge,
he says,
wa ma hu ti tum min al
ilmillah qalila.
So, we've not given you from
knowledge
except a little.
So, Allah is alamu in every
circumstance
and in every situation.
So, if you are not saying
anything,
and you say Allahu alamu,
yes, what you said is true.
If you explain and yet you
come
back and say Allahu alamu,
it's also true.
So, in any case,
Allahu is alamu.
But, make sure that you are
not
employing that situation,
that expression to imply any
sort of
a deceit or the likes of
that.
No, don't deceive the people
using these
kinds of expressions.